>> git init        - Initialize a new Git repository
>> git clone       - Copy a remote repository to local system
>> git add         - Stage files to prepare for commit
>> git commit      - Save staged changes permanently
>> git status      - Show current status of working directory
>> git log         - Show commit history
>> git branch      - List, create, or delete branches
>> git checkout    - Switch branches
>> git merge       - Merge changes from another branch
>> git push        - Upload local commits to GitHub
